FALDO JULIAN JOSHUA LAOH

| faldolaoh357@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/faldolaoh | https://tinyurl.com/FaldoPortfolio

My name is Faldo Julian Joshua Laoh, i'am a sophomore undergraduate student of Infromation System at UPN "Veteran" Jawa Timur. Passionate in UI/UX Design and Web Development. I learnt how to manages systems and also learnt how the create a proper structure to the software project that'd been executed, such learning how to build a Design System based on the users needs by doing the UX Research and also make the proper flow for user to enhanced effectivity and efficiency on the System that been made. besides of that, i'am also an adaptable, teamworker person with great leadership and time managament skill

Education Level

Universitas Pembangunan Nasional Veteran Jawa Timur - Surabaya, East Java

2022 - Present

Undergraduate in Information Systems, 3.85/4.00

- One of the highest GPA of all the class of 2022
- Being HTML & CSS Practitioner in Short Class at SMPN 1 Waru, Sidoarjo

Experiences

Team Leader - Proto-a- thon UI/UX Competition - Bekasi, West

May 2024 - Jun 2024

Java

Binus University Bekasi, West Java

- Being a Team Leader that manages team member to be worked as one to make a greater output
- Make decisions which Features should and should not include in a feature in app that will be build. As the result, Our main and
 original features has been praised by the jury for being a well prepared and original idea
- Make sure everything goes as plan without any off schedule activity
- Using a Design skill to manage to propper visual to implemented in the app, and make sure it has to be an visually easy to use
 design app. as the result, our app design is very well designed by the jury with with more than 75% of direct success usability testing

HIPSTER - HackFest Competition - Surabaya, East Java

Dec 2023 - Jan 2024

Google Developer Students Club Indonesia

- Being the Head of the UI/UX Design as a Hipster
- Making Design that usable and very easy to understand by any range of age
- · Making easy to see visual and make a Design that able to make an interesting thought from people
- Brainstorming and Make an ordinary idea from scratch and match them with all the stakeholder needs into a visual feature app

Semifinalist RISE! Business Case Competition - Surabaya,

Aug 2023 - Nov 2023

East Java

Information System Expo! ITS Surabaya

- Decision Making on how to solve some of the case study problem =
- Making solution on how to solve the cases and make the effective way to make to case easier, as the result, our team made one of the best solutions.
- Team work skills on how to communicate on one and another member, sharing all opinions and make the best output by blending all of them together as one

Organisational & Volunteering Experience

Orientasi Mahasiswa Kristen Baru (OMKB) 2023 - Prigen, East Java

Jun 2023 - Sep 2023

Member of Fundraise Division

- Being able to mark up a strategy on how to effectively make a money on something. As the result, there are 4 of 9 new jobdesc that have been added to make a more progressive income
- Make a great team work by doing everything together as one and fullfill the need of one and another
- Make a great communication skills by discussing and announcing program into another division of the commitee

UPNVJT Christmas Event 2023 - Surabaya, East Java

Nov 2023 - Dec 2023

Head of Fundraise Division

- Leadership skills by being the role model of my team member, and also able to manages them on doing all of their workdesc with a help of a hand, so that they were'nt work by themselfs
- Problem solving on make a solution how to manages some workdesc problem that didn't go as planned, and make a new way to make it propperly done in time. As the result, most of the workdescs were being done within or before the deadline.
- Making a target more than the predetermined target just in case their a urgent needs in the other division. As the result, my division surplussed the target by 80% and been done far away before the deadline.

Projects

SukeRT - UI/UX Design Website & Front end Web Program

Jun 2024

SukeRT is an website designed to make a letter acceptance of RT easier than before, by providing them with online form to fill and auto generate letter with approval of the RT themselves as fast as possible.

- Designing the website as simple as possible, since the target users is middle agers in average.
- Doing research by 1on1 deep-interview with the RT and the People to make sure all their needs is included in the website Code it as a website using HTML and Vanilla CSS with the desktop size design

Equipp.ed - UI/UX Design Application

May 024 - Jun 2024

Equipp.ed is an app designed to improve learning process and assist students with disabilities

- Being able to think of an original feature, 80% of the feature was originally made as the unique feature and was praised by the jury because of it.
- Being a team leader that manages each member workdesc to make a stable and efficient work atmosphere for each member
- Finding the needs of the target customer what they need and make it to the visually pleasing design.

EasePark - UI/UX Design Application

Dec 2023 - Jan 2024

EasePark is an Designed app that helps people with their parking problem by providing them with online payment parking and integrated it with RFID technology.

- Team working to make the best solution on the study case, and make a research on how visual affecting the user.
- Finding out the user need by doing some quantitative research to calculate how desperate people with this study case
- Designing a simple visuals, to make users comfortable and able to use the app with ease.

•

Skills, Achievements & Other Experience

- Hard Skills (2024): UI/UX Design, Graphic Design, HTML, CSS, PHP
- Soft Skills (2024): Public Speaking, Team Work, Adaptibility, Leadership, Critical Thinking, Time Management
- Languages: Bahasa Indonesia (Native), English (Limited Working Proficiency)